Mahira Hamzah

Senior Manufacturing Engineer | Aspiring Data Scientist



Email: mahirahamzah@gmail.com

About Me



You can call me Aira.

Currently pursuing Master in Data Science & Analytics at University Sains Malaysia, expected to graduate in 2021 and working full-time at Western Digital as Senior Manufacturing Engineer.

I mostly code in C# and R at work but I do my projects for data analytics mostly related to machine learning in Python. I just recently certified as AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner.

Since March 2020, the topic of COVID-19 has been trendy topic in Kaggle and I recently decided to join the bandwagon. My project

for COVID-19 Malaysia can be found here Github, Kaggle Dataset and Kaggle Notebook

Experience

Western Digital (Media)

westerndigital.com

Senior Manufacturing

Engineer

Feb 2020 - Present

Despite the title, my task is actually more like fullstack software developer. I'm building an application system to replace manual calculation by engineers. The web application is build using MVC architecture with some R for analytics.

Drive Global Tool of Specification (GTOS) process and Automation Capability Management (ACM) Buyoff for One-of-a-Kind (OOAK) machines equipped with SECS/GEM capabilities. Create test plans for SECS/GEM buyoff, perform black-box testing on the application features or enhancements.

OSRAM Opto Semiconductor

osram.com

Computer Integrated Manufacturing Engineer April 2018 - January 2020

Infineon Technologies

infineon.com

Equipment Automation Engineer

I started my career with zero knowledge about semiconductor but 3 years in Infineon accorded me with broad knowledge especially regarding automation fab technologies. I successfully integrated more than 40 machines into the system and became subject

February 2015 - March 2019

matter experts for Implanter and Preassembly process integration. I was also the team lead for final system verification during major shutdown. Whilst at Infineon I had the opportunity to work with: SECS/GEM, MES, OpenSIM Pro

Education

University Sains Malaysia

Master in Data Science & Analytics Current CGPA: 3.22

2018 - 2021

Founded on 1 June 1969 as a statutory body with its own constitution, among the oldest institutes of higher learning in Northern Malaysia. USM is the only Accelerated Programs for Excellence (APEX) government-funded autonomous university in Malaysia.

This master program aims to produce manpower / human resources in the field of Big Data Analytics which capable of making decisions based on the availability of comprehensive data. I've gained knowledge on understanding of the core concepts, practice and tools in the domain of data science and analytics. I also learned the skills of collecting and integrating data, modelling and advanced big data analysis. Full course syllabus can be found here

University Teknologi Malaysia

Universiti Teknologi Malaysia (UTM) is a Malaysian public researchintensive university in engineering, science and technology. Top 10 University in South East Asia according to Quacquarelli Symonds (QS) World University Rankings Bachelor in Computer Science (Database System) CGPA: 3.64 Dean's Award 2010 - 2014

This course is currently has been rebrand to Data Engineering with some updated syllabus to cater with current technology needs but with still overall same fundamental. I was exposed to specialization in the database field with the combination of computer science, database technology and information technology. Full course syllabus can be found here

Certifications

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner

https://www.youracclaim.com/badges/aef52f68-0227-4d89-a990-f45840dc7456/public_url **AWS 2020**

ITIL® Foundation Certificate in IT Service Management

EXIN 2017 Credential ID: 5978101.20652803

Oracle Database 11g Database Associate

https://www.youracclaim.com/badges/acac5063-fa9b-444d-8af9-060a29ae703e/public_url

Oracle 2013

IC3 Digital Literacy Certification

A Little More About Me

When I'm not programming, I like to read book while having cuppa coffee. I've been living in Penang, Malaysia since 2018 and falling in love with cafe scene here. My personal fav is Ome by Spacebar Coffee. I also enjoy outdoors activities especially hiking. You can take a peek of all these in my instagram: @aira.hmzh

I used to be active host for couchsurfing in Penang @Airahamzah, however since CS started to charge for membership I'm considering moving to other platforms but yet to register. The reason why I like hosting because It allowed me to meet people from all over the world, who will sometimes cook for me, clean for me, and most of time have amazing stories to tell. It's like traveling while staying home! It makes me more culturally aware, give me new connections and friends.

Mahira Hamzah - mahirahamzah@gmail.com